Guide to the California Letters, 1852-1858
Department of Special Collections
California Letters, 1852-1858
Special Collections M0038
Gibbons, A. S. Gibbons, Sarah Cloud Krebs, James A.
29 items
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Provenance:
Gift of George Coffin Taylor
Access Restrictions
None.
Scope and Contents Note:
The bulk of this collection consists of twenty letters by A. S. Gibbons and/or his wife Sarah Cloud Gibbons to her family in Virginia, 1852 to 1857. A. S. Gibbons was an itinerant Methodist preacher who spent one year teaching at Santa Clara College. The letters primarily consist of descriptions of domestic problems and the temperance movement.
Other items in the collection include five letters concerning James A. Krebs, a prospecter, 1854-1858; a letter addressed to H. H. Heath dated July 22, 1854 concerning schools and law practice in San Francisco; and one page of an unidentified diary for June 1852.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence of A. S. Gibbons and Sarah Cloud Gibbons: (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Sarah to "Brother Bobbie." Benicia, CA, 1852 June 15
  - Sarah to "Sister Lutie" and father. Benicia, 1852 June 15
  - Sarah to parents. Benicia, 1852 June 23
  - Sarah to parents. Benicia, 1853 Aug. 12
  - Sarah to "Sister Lutie." Benicia, 1853 Jan. 12
  - A. S. Gibbons to "Bro. Daniel." Columbia, CA, 1853 April 19
  - Sarah to mother. Columbia, 1 853 April 23
  - Sarah to "Brother Bobbie." Columbia, 1853 June 3
  - Sarah to "Sister Lutie." Columbia, 1853 June 6
  - A. S. Gibbons and Sarah to parents. Columbia, 1853 Dec. 26
  - Sarah to parents. Santa Clara, CA, 1854 Sept. 14
  - Sarah to parents. Santa Clara, CA, 1854 Nov. 14
  - Sarah to parents. Santa Clara, CA, 1855 Jan. 28
  - Sarah to father and mother. Santa Clara, 1856 June 3
  - Sarah to "Sister Ginnie." San Jose, CA, 1856 July 3
  - Sarah to parents. Santa Clara, 1856 Sept. 2
  - A. S. Gibbons to parents. Coloma, CA, 1856 Dec. 17
  - Sarah to parents. Coloma, 1857 April 3
  - Sarah to sister. Coloma, 1857 May 2
  - Sarah to father and mother. Coloma, 1857 June 2
- Typescript copies of original correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Original letters of: (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - James A. Krebs to father. Ouseleys Bar, 1854 Oct. 23
  - J. A. Krebs to father. Ouseley's Bar, Yuba County, 1856 Nov. 10
  - J. A. Krebs to sister. Ouseleys Bar, Yuba Co., 1857 Feb. 8
  - R. B. Sherrard, Marysville, CA 1858 Nov. 18
  - Wm. H. Campbell to Judge R. B. Sherrard. Fort Gale, Fraser River, 1858 Aug. 13.Note added from Robert to Dear Father
  - (Shorb) to H. H. Heath. San Francisco, 1854 July 22
  - Wm. D. Jeffreys to J. O. Jeffreys, Louistown, CA, 1855 July 21
  - Diary 1852 June 5 to June 9,one page. Author unidentified
  - (Jennie) to My Dear Teacher. 1853 March 15